STEVE J. **THOMPSON**

3609 Hedgewood Dr., Columbia, MO 65203 | H: (573) 446-6634 | C: (573) 356-9044 | steve@stevejthompson.com

CAREER OVERVIEW

Seasoned Full Stack Web Developer with comprehensive technical skills and expertise in Web Design, HTML, CSS, PHP, WordPress, Magento, vBulletin, jQuery, Server Administration & Security, MySQL, SEO, PhoneGap, Usability and IT Applications. Proficient problem solver that has creative ideas, a strong passion for work, team development and leadership.

QUALIFICATIONS AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Full stack web developer
- Proficient in PHP, HTML5, CSS3, JS
- Mobile frameworks (Bootstrap, Foundation)
- Landing page development
- Project management
- Strong collaborative skills
- Code validation and optimization
- ADA compliance and accessibility
- Strong leadership skills
- Management experience

- Excellent problem solving skills
- Content management systems (WordPress, Drupal)
- Strong knowledge of PHP platforms (Magento, OSCommerce, vBulletin, Xenforo)
- Server management (Linux and Windows)
- Server security, optimizing and performance tuning
- Strong analytical skills

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Created a uniform web identity for MU School of Medicine and its 22 individual departments.
- Developed an in-house, custom content management system that housed over 100 websites throughout the entire MU Health System.
- Custom built and maintained all web servers for MU Health System.
- Managed small team of web developers and instituted a continual quality improvement process (Total Quality Control) to ensure websites remained fresh, accessible and kept clients happy.
- Maintained a successful free-lance business with over 100 hosted clients for over 10 years.
- Created one of the largest unofficial Final Fantasy websites (thefinalfantasy.com) which at one point was getting 5k visitors a day (the site is over 15 years old and currently being redesigned). Use this site to test SEO and currently #1 on Google for keyword 'final fantasy games'.
- Created large ecommerce website for a client (sweetdreamsquiltstudio.com) using OSCommerce (currently migrating to Magento). The site has over 12,000 virtual products that auto-encrypt on the server during checkout. Website has grossed over 1 million in 10 years.
- Created a custom web application to help hundreds of medical students during the advising process (CATSA) (catsa.missouri.edu).
- Helped create an online mortgage/financial bidding tool (ratebid.com)
- Created an Android app using PhoneGap (still in development)

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2013 to 01/2016 Web Manager

University of Missouri Health System - Columbia, MO

Managed web development team for MU Health Care, School of Medicine and other divisions of the health system through these activities:

- Oversight on all web components and coordinated with marketing, public relations and leadership to enrich our web identity, promote mission/values of institution, and stay aligned with strategic goals.
- Managed multiple web servers and collaborated with Cerner/Tiger Institute on front-end web applications to improve patient-centered care and overall usability.
- Began initiative to make all websites mobile-friendly, ADA compliant and follow new identity guidelines.
- Publish and manage web content, while effectively communicating with clients to ensure accuracy and over-the-top satisfaction.

Managed group of programmers and instituted continual quality checks (Total Quality Control).

05/2010 to 03/2013

Programmer/Analyst - Expert

MU School of Medicine - Columbia, MO

Web development and programming for the entire School of Medicine through these activities:

- Designed, programmed, and maintained websites for the School, departments, divisions and offices.
- Collaborated internally to ensure communication and consistency for the web school-wide. Introduced a new 'identity' with a uniform design and was able to get 21 out of 22 departments on board using strong interpersonal skills.
- Administered web servers (Linux and Windows) to ensure all websites were secure and complied with campus-wide policies.

05/2006 to 05/2010 Programmer/Analyst - Entry

Strategic Technologies Group - Columbia, MO

Worked as web programmer through these activities:

- Designed, programmed, and maintained websites for the University of Missouri, Cerner Corporation and other companies/businesses.
- Worked with team of designers, modelers and programmers on YouZeum project that featured exhibits that helped students learn the human body.

08/2004 to Current IT Consultant

Fishline Media - Columbia, MO

Provide custom web design, development, SEO and marketing:

- Designed, coded and implemented business websites to over 100 clients locally and nationally.
- Remotely managed my own web servers and for multiple clients.
- Remotely managed programmers and designers to meet project goals and deadlines.
- Strong open source experience and ability to use any framework to create custom solutions.

07/2003 to 05/2006 Web Development Intern

Division of IT - Columbia, MO

Designed and developed websites for large and small departments campus-wide through these activities:

- Developed custom PHP/JS scripts to create dynamic and original websites.
- Converted custom designs provided by designers from Photoshop to HTML.

EDUCATION

2007

Bachelor of Science: Business Management University of Missouri - Columbia, MÖ, United States Includes a Minor in Computer Science (30 credited hours)

AWARDS AND TRAINING

- ExpertRating HTML 4.1 Certified (ISO 9001-2000 Standard)
- 2001 DECA Regional Championship Award --- Excellence in Business Development.
- Senator Joe Moseley Citizenship Award
- AAMC 2013 Careers in Medicine Professional Development Conference
- Geonetric 2013 eHealth Symposium